<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Riptide Rhythm</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Riptide Rhythm</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-EN</language>
    <copyright>All rights reserved - 2015</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 16:36:04 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EVH 5150</title>
      <link>/post/evh-5150/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Jan 2019 16:36:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/evh-5150/</guid>
      <description>I am a person to steer away from signature amps because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to sound like someone else but the 5150 is really not a signature anymore. It is more of a staple in the Metal music scene. This creation of theses amps started with Peavey but EVH broke off after the contract came to an end and became its own brand. Fender is the company that currently making the current era of 5150 amps that you can purchase today.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Boss GT-1000</title>
      <link>/post/boss-gt-1000/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Nov 2018 20:26:09 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/boss-gt-1000/</guid>
      <description>This is out of the norm for me. I prefer tubes and boxes because of their ease of use. I maybe a programmer by day but music is my escape for that world so I tend to stear towards things that wont require a computer. With that said, I am a fan of the Boss Katana amp and how it sounded which this is based of the Katana and Waza technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Horizon Devices Precision Drive</title>
      <link>/post/horizon-devices-precision-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Mar 2018 16:15:25 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/horizon-devices-precision-drive/</guid>
      <description>No one paid me for this. Honest opinions.
Overview Misha Mansoor&amp;rsquo;s Horizon Devices released their first product a while back called the Precision Drive but people keep asking me for my opinion since I own one. This pedal is an overdrive pedal designed for modern metal, not your dad&amp;rsquo;s metal. The pedal was built by MXR, so it is definitely durable. It has passed my strenuous and thorough toddler testing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Les Paul (finishing)</title>
      <link>/post/diy-les-paul-finishing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2017 14:02:17 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/diy-les-paul-finishing/</guid>
      <description>Blue Finish  No Lacquer Finish  Lacquered Unbuffed Finish  After the first telecaster kit, I wanted to do a full kit without a pre-finished body. I am going to break this whole into a couple of posts and I want to focus on finishing a guitar and how I approached this Les Paul.I wanted a Les Paul when you could still see the flame or quilted maple and the one that I loved came out of the Gibson Custom Shop.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DIY Guitar Kit</title>
      <link>/post/diy-guitar-kits/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 23:42:04 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/diy-guitar-kits/</guid>
      <description>So I decided it was time. I am tired of buying guitars that aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly what I want. I always end up replacing everything in the guitar, from the nut and the strings to the electronics. I decided that I needed a guitar with single coil pickups. I am a Stratocaster person so I decided that it was time to build a Telecaster. I like my guitars at the opposite ends of the spectrum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedalboards</title>
      <link>/post/pedalboards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 21:24:01 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/pedalboards/</guid>
      <description>When starting out with pedals, the hardest thing to do is decide what kind of pedalboard you should get. I struggled with this and everyone does. You don&amp;rsquo;t know where to start or what to get. When you first start digging, you will come across Velcro, mounts, or zip ties. Velcro is the most common of the three. So, I will try to explain the cons of each then let you decide for yourself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Know thy Power</title>
      <link>/post/know-thy-power/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2017 22:05:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/know-thy-power/</guid>
      <description>These are the most common questions that I get asked when people first get started.
 How should I power my pedals? Should I use 9v or 18v? Why do you need a clean power supply? What is wrong with a daisy chain?  So many questions on what you would believe to be a simple topic, right? Actually, this is where the most common mistakes are made. I have seen people fry pedals and make a really good sounding pedal sound really bad just from giving it the wrong voltage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Earthquaker Devices Space Spiral</title>
      <link>/post/eqd-space-spiral/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Feb 2017 20:54:51 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/eqd-space-spiral/</guid>
      <description>Earthquaker Devices, or EQD has always been a pedal company that drastically changes your tone. They are very experimental and most of the time, amazing. The Space Spiral does not drift from that line of thinking. It is analog delay with a modulated sound much like the 70&amp;rsquo;s sci-fi era.
If you are wanting a normal analog delay or don&amp;rsquo;t like the experimental sounds that EQD, then just stop reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s with all the Wood?</title>
      <link>/post/whats-with-all-the-wood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 21:15:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/whats-with-all-the-wood/</guid>
      <description>Oh man, pick/plectrum materials are now becoming a highly debatable topic. I never thought I would see the day but it is here. There is wood, acrylic, Celluloid, tortex, Ultex (polyetherimide), UHMWPE (Ultra-high-molecular-weight polyethylene), Nylon, Delrin, stone, metal, bone, or glass. So, there are a bunch of big words for &amp;ldquo;fancy&amp;rdquo; plastic and a few others. I could go on but nevertheless, there is a boutique market for picks to be explored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walrus Audio Red High-Gain Distortion</title>
      <link>/post/walrus-audio-red/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2017 21:00:02 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/walrus-audio-red/</guid>
      <description>I have not been paid for this review.
Overview  Walrus Audio unveiled at NAMM &amp;lsquo;17 their new distortion, &amp;ldquo;Red&amp;rdquo;. It&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;take no prisioners&amp;rdquo; distortion. It contains an active EQ, volume, and gain controls, along with a &amp;ldquo;texture&amp;rdquo; switch as well as true-bypass. The &amp;ldquo;texture&amp;rdquo; switch toggles between an uncompressed, overdrive-like sound and a more compressed, tightened sound.
The Pedal  I like some high-gain in my distortion pedals but this adds a little sparkle that is hard to wrap my words around it but it is what makes this pedal unique.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>